<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Building</title>
        <author email="meikel@meikel.at">Meikel</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Building the Project">
            <subsection name="Introduction">
                <p>It is necessary to build the software before you can use it. If you downloaded the project to your
                    machine and unzipped the file, then you obtained a directory containing the source code. The source
                    code
                    is
                    a human readable
                    <sup>[<a name="id.humanReadable" href="#ftn.humanReadable">1</a>]
                    </sup>
                    specification of the software which can not be executed by a machine e.g. your
                    computer. The source code has to be transformed in a representation which can be understood by the
                    machine. This process of transforming some source code is called &quot;compilation&quot;. Compiling
                    all
                    source files of the whole project is called &quot;building the project&quot;. As a result of
                    building
                    the project you'll receive an artifact called jar. This jar is needed to run the Excel
                    Converter.This
                    document describes the steps you have to complete to build the project.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Setting up the SDK">
                <p>First of all you need to set up a Java SDK to build the project. The Java SDK is the software
                    containing the compiler. To set up the Java SDK you need to install the software and then set the
                    environment variable
                    <code>JAVA_HOME</code>
                    to the location where you installed the Java SDK. Here you can find some basic instructions how to
                    <a href="http://openjdk.java.net/install/">install OpenJDK</a>. When installing the Java SDK
                    you should pay attention to not install a JRE (Java Runtime Environment), because this is not
                    intended to compile source code, instead of that it is used to run the compiled artifacts.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Setting up Maven">
                <p>After you installed the Java SDk you have a compiler available which could be used to compile the
                    source code of the project. Since the project comprises many source files it would be a cumbersome
                    task to compile the whole project, because it's difficult to call the compiler by hand. To simplify
                    the process of building the whole project there are available so called build tools. The build tool
                    used to build this project is called Maven, so as the next step you've to set up Maven.
                </p>
                <p>Just download the latest Maven 3.x binary zip from the
                    <a href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html">
                        Maven download site
                    </a>. You'll receive a zip file which you have to unzip somewhere on your hard disk. Then you need
                    to set
                    the environment variable
                    <code>M2_HOME</code>
                    to point to the location where you unzipped Maven. Furthermore you have to add
                    <code>${M2_HOME}/bin</code>
                    to your
                    <code>PATH</code>
                    to be able to call Maven from the command line. To verify that you installed Maven correctly open a
                    shell and enter the command
                    <source>mvn -v</source>
                    which should print the version of your Maven installation. If you run call this command
                    successfully,
                    then you are ready to build the Excel Converter.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Building">
                <p>TODO</p>
                <macro name="snippet">
                    <param name="id" value="building"/>
                    <param name="file" value="src/site/resources/building.txt"/>
                </macro>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Running the Excel Converter">
                <p>Here you find instructions on
                    <a href="running.html">running the Excel Converter</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section name="Footnotes">
            <div class="footnote">
                <sup>[<a name="ftn.humanReadable" href="#id.humanReadable">1</a>]
                </sup>
                At least the source code is human readable if you're a programmer. Otherwise it's not human
                readable.
            </div>
        </section>
    </body>

</document>